Finding Aid for the Anne Waldman Papers, 1945-2012
Anne Waldman Papers
- Writing
  - Poetry
    - Single Titles
      - Invitation To A Picture Hanging, for Jasper Johns [note attached, "Poems for Painters?"] (Box 37)
      - Invocation for Raising Windhorse (Box 37)
      - Iovis Omnia Plena [w/note, "draft of Kerouac Section Iovis I"] (Box 37)
      - is it happening [fl] (Box 37)
      - Is You (Box 37)
      - It Sounds It (Box 37)
      - Italian City Sonnet (Box 37)
      - Jabs, to Ted Berrigan (Box 37)
      - Jackie Curtis [with clipping] (Box 37)
      - Jane was exceedingly plain [fl; includes other limericks] (Box 37)
      - Journal Nicaragua (Box 37)
      - Jump (Box 37)
      - Jumpin' with My Friend Memory (Box 37)
      - Jurassic (Box 37)
      - Just to Swoon in Another Way (Box 37)
      - Kali Yuga Blues (Box 37)
      - Kill or Cure [one version missing p. 1] (Box 37)
      - Killin Floor Blues (Box 37)
      - Kind Of [plus another poem, "The Mirror"] (Box 37)
      - L (Box 37)
      - Lad of the Malign (Box 37)
      - Lady on a Rooster (looking at a picture of a Hindu goddess), for Angelica Clark (Box 37)
      - Last Night (Box 37)
      - Last Poem (Box 37)
      - Legend of Desire to Rule Water [plus "Request," "To Down a Phantom," and other material] (Box 37)
      - Legs (Box 37)
      - Lent (Box 37)
      - Lesson [includes poem "Election"] (Box 37)
      - Lethal Blue, for Amber (Box 37)
      - Letter to Miss Idona Hand [plus "What are you?"] (Box 37)
      - Libertad (Box 37)
      - Light & Shadow (Box 37)
      - light/ shadow/ shine [first lines] (Box 37)
      - Lines for Elio Schneeman (Box 37)
      - Lines to a Celebrated Friend [for Allen Ginsberg] (Box 37)
      - Lives of Great Men (Box 37)
      - Lokapala (Box 37)
      - Long As (Box 37)
      - lore (Box 37)
      - Los Caprichos [or "The Hermitage," "The Eske"] (Box 37)
      - Loud Concerts (Box 37)
      - Love Letter, for Steven Lowe (Box 37)
      - Love Poem (Box 37)
      - Love's Tombstone (Box 37)
      - Lullaby (Box 37)
      - Mclure (Box 37)
      - Magician, for Susan Hall (Box 37)
      - Mahadeviyakka Speaks [from the Therigatha or the Theragatha ?] (Box 37)
      - Mahayana Lament (Box 37)
      - Malachite [plus "Nootka Love Song" and Frank O'Hara quote] (Box 37)
      - Mammalian, undated (Box 37)
      - Man Traveling [title deleted] (Box 37)
      - Managua Sketches [one version missing last page] (Box 37)
      - Manifesto (Box 37)
      - many/ advocations/ or/ alterations [first lines; fragment?] (Box 37)
      - Marianne Moore reading (Box 37)
      - Mark/ you there [first lines; "for Mark Sikelianos on Ruth's death"] (Box 37)
      - Mars (Box 37)
      - Martyrology (Box 37)
      - Matriarchly (Box 37)
      - Mauve Flowers of the Ubiquitous Wisteria ["from Cabin"] (Box 37)
      - Men & Women (Box 37)
      - Mesa (Box 37)
      - Mesmer (Box 37)
      - Miami (Democratic Convention) (Box 37)
      - Michael caught a little sunfish [fl; collaboration, possibly written w/Michael (Brownstein?)?] (Box 37)
      - Midnight Snacks [a version also appears as "After-Dinner Entertaining"] (Box 37)
      - Mirage (Box 37)
      - Model Folding In The Reign Of Tut Equals Voltri XIX, [for?] David Smith (Box 37)
      - Monochrome (Night) (Box 37)
      - Mother's Curse [missing p. 2-?] (Box 37)
      - Mountains! Mountains! [fl] (Box 37)
      - Mummy Case of Artemidorus with Painted Portrait (Box 37)
      - Muse (Box 37)
      - Mushroom (Box 37)
      - My Credo (Box 37)
      - My Own Eyes Did This Sonnet (Box 37)
      - Name, for John Waldman (Box 38)
      - Names & Places, from a Journal (Box 38)
      - Narcolepsy [with Ted Berrigan] (Box 38)
      - Nerves (Box 38)
      - Net Life [and "Panegyric"] (Box 38)
      - New Landlord (Box 38)
      - New Year Sing Air [or "The Don Season"?] (Box 38)
      - Night Wing (Box 38)
      - 9 Mechanical Poems, for Ron (Box 38)
      - Nine O'clock [includes "Diction" and "To Love"] (Box 38)
      - 19 objects laid out on the table can I remember them all? [fl; poem or journal entry?] (Box 38)
      - No Fun Lung (Box 38)
      - No man's eye has ever [fl] (Box 38)
      - No Nonsense (Box 38)
      - No Suffer (Box 38)
      - No way out of nicotine [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - Nomad's Song (Box 38)
      - Not Done (Box 38)
      - Notes on Sitting Beside a Noble Corpse [Full title, "Notes on Sitting Beside a Noble Corpse--Light Breeze Stirring the Curtains, Blue--Faint Tremor of His Blue Shroud"] (Box 38)
      - notes watching Douglas Dunn dance, 1975 (Box 38)
      - Notorious [note attached, "from Fast Speaking Woman"] (Box 38)
      - (November) Language Has Wings (Box 38)
      - Nutrient (Box 38)
      - O Husband! (Box 38)
      - O I See (Box 38)
      - O I See How, Now, for Chogyam Trungpa, Rinpoche (Box 38)
      - O Moon (Box 38)
      - Object Notes [by Anne Waldman?] (Box 38)
      - Ode to 437 East 12th (Box 38)
      - Ode to Last Night (Box 38)
      - Ode To My Skirts (Box 38)
      - Ode to Speech (Box 38)
      - Off (Box 38)
      - Old Dream Ritual (Box 38)
      - Old Homage Ritual, for Jerry (Box 38)
      - Om Tare Tutth Tare Sarva Artha Siddhi Siddhi Kuru Swaha [p. 2 related?] (Box 38)
      - On Being Painted, by Alex Katz (Box 38)
      - On Considering Certain Personal Attacks [eventually "Under My Breath"; attached note on one draft, "from Kill or Cure"] (Box 38)
      - On East Hill, for Edwin Denby (Box 38)
      - On Memorial Day I forget everything, exquisite corpse collaboration with "Bernadette, Lewis, Jack, Reed, Anne, Steve Malmude, Carol, Allison" (Box 38)
      - On My Birthday (Box 38)
      - On what is her liveliness rooted? [fl; fragment? Last page related?] (Box 38)
      - One Night Stand ["Kenward Elmslie song"] (Box 38)
      - One Taste (Box 38)
      - Open Address to Senator Jesse Helms (Box 38)
      - Orchids & Mum (Box 38)
      - Ostensive [plus "Rondure"] (Box 38)
      - Our Past [attached note, "Blue Mosque"] (Box 38)
      - Ousted (Box 38)
      - Out There (Box 38)
      - Paean: May I Speak Thus? (Box 38)
      - Painted Ships on Which the Little Ships Ride, for Reed [attached note, "from Makeup on Empty Space "] (Box 38)
      - Palinode (Walk) (Box 38)
      - Panegyric (Box 38)
      - Parable [by Anne Waldman or another?] (Box 38)
      - Paraphrase of Edwin Denby on the "New York School" (Box 38)
      - Past Life (Box 38)
      - Patacara Speaks [from the Therigatha or the Theragatha ] (Box 38)
      - paying for heat [fl; poem?] (Box 38)
      - Pearls of India (Box 38)
      - People Coming Up the Stairs (Box 38)
      - Performance (Box 38)
      - Peripatetic (Box 38)
      - Persephone (Box 38)
      - Petrarch (Box 38)
      - Philosophia Perennis (Box 38)
      - Phone Dictation (Box 38)
      - Photograph (Box 38)
      - Pictures of Poets (Box 38)
      - Picturesque (Box 38)
      - Pieces Of An Hour (Box 38)
      - Pink Lady (Box 38)
      - Pitch (Box 38)
      - Pith Alarum [partial] (Box 38)
      - Plane Work: Rattle Up A Deer [attached note, "Pub. in Journals & Dreams 'plane work' w/B.M."; with Bernadette Mayer] (Box 38)
      - Plutonium Chant (Box 38)
      - Poem (Box 38)
      - Poem Elegiac (Box 38)
      - Poem en Forme de la Bouche (Box 38)
      - Poem for Charles North (Box 38)
      - Poem for Jim Carroll (Box 38)
      - Poem for Ramsey Clark (Box 38)
      - Poem for the Streets of New York City (Box 38)
      - Poem from Bed (Box 38)
      - Poem to Michael Wagner [per attached note] (Box 38)
      - Poems & Notes & Letters from a Journal (South America), July 1972 (Box 38)
      - Poems [from "Fast Speaking Woman" and "Some of the Things I See for You"] (Box 38)
      - Poets (Box 38)
      - Polemic (Box 38)
      - Postcard from Tairona Colombia, SA [original title or subtitle "Dear Bernadette"] (Box 38)
      - Practices of the Night [correct p. 3 or no?] (Box 38)
      - Pressure (Box 38)
      - priests part/devoted throng [first lines; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - Private Rooms (Box 38)
      - Protection Amulets [and "Amulets," from among loose notes on travels, originally from a journal?] (Box 38)
      - Puer ["later part of Iovis I"] (Box 38)
      - Putting Makeup on Empty Space (Box 38)
      - Pygmy Heaven (Box 38)
      - Questions for DD [Douglas Dunn] (Box 38)
      - Questions for Kenneth Koch (Box 38)
      - Quick Alchemy [review] (Box 38)
      - Ram, for Anselm (Box 38)
      - Recent Correspondence (Box 38)
      - Red Faces [by Gertrude Stein] (Box 38)
      - Red Hat Lama (Box 38)
      - Redonda (Box 38)
      - Reds (She Makes Sense Of Her Surroundings) (Box 38)
      - Reed Bye (Box 38)
      - replenish making twine if you like, for Andrew (Box 38)
      - Request (for 2 female voices), in homage John Giorno (Box 38)
      - Resisting Each Other (Box 38)
      - Resplendent Things (Box 38)
      - Revenge [handwritten draft, may contain additional material] (Box 38)
      - Rex Iudeorum (Box 38)
      - Robert Lowell, for Creeley (Box 38)
      - Rocky Flats: Relative Truth from the Warring God Realm: An Investigative Poetics, dedicated to Ed Sanders (Box 38)
      - Ronaural (Box 38)
      - Rondeau (Box 38)
      - Rooms (Box 38)
      - Rudeste (Box 38)
      - Rushing in the dark last night [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - Russian Nelli (Box 38)
      - Sad Cypress (Box 38)
      - Saint (Box 38)
      - St. Mark's Place (Box 38)
      - Sandinista (Box 38)
      - Sat A.M. (Box 38)
      - Schiaparelli (Box 38)
      - Scientist (Box 38)
      - Seattle (Box 38)
      - Seldom Here (Box 38)
      - Self Other Both Neither (Box 38)
      - Sending & Receiving (Box 38)
      - Sestina (Box 38)
      - Sex and Intrigue (She Seduces A Terrorist & Has To Leave Town), for Kathy Acker [two of the drafts: p. 1 only] (Box 38)
      - Shapely Writing (Box 38)
      - She (Box 38)
      - She Chant (Box 38)
      - Shirt, for Gertrude (Box 38)
      - Silent Man, for Carl (Box 38)
      - Silver E (Box 38)
      - Similar Alike (Box 38)
      - Sine Qua Non Coccoon (Box 38)
      - Sister Death (Box 38)
      - Sisters (Box 38)
      - Skin Meat Bones (Box 38)
      - Slide Piana [or "Slide Piano"] (Box 38)
      - Sober Up [alternate title "Sobering"] (Box 38)
      - Some Notes (Box 38)
      - Some Things in the House that are Joe Brainard (Box 38)
      - Something for You (Box 38)
      - Some of the Things I See for You, for Michael (Box 38)
      - Sonnet (Box 38)
      - Sophisticated Poem (Box 38)
      - Sounds like doors to me [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - South (Box 38)
      - Speech (Box 38)
      - Spending Money (Box 38)
      - Split (Box 38)
      - Squawk! [fl] (Box 38)
      - Step Any Talk Back a Step (Box 38)
      - Stileto [sic] (Box 38)
      - Strange Days Ahead [review of Michael Brownstein book, Strange Days Ahead ] (Box 38)
      - Summer Plans [or "Streaks remembering Frances"] (Box 38)
      - Suppose a Game [early title, "The Agreement"] (Box 38)
      - "Susan" (and "Mary") (Box 38)
      - Suspicion (Box 38)
      - Swanity (Box 38)
      - Swiss Banker (Box 38)
      - Taking Gary Snyder to the Airport (Box 38)
      - Tall Town Stun, for Yvonne (Box 38)
      - T.C. (Box 38)
      - Teardrops (Box 38)
      - Teen Angel (Box 38)
      - Tell A Story About A Threshold Here (Box 38)
      - Telling You (Box 38)
      - Ten Books Are Sustaining (Box 38)
      - Thanksgiving November Fall on[?] Birthday (Box 38)
      - The brow sweeps the sky like a rainbow [fl] (Box 38)
      - "The Clean Air and the Open Window Invite Me to Write to You" (Box 38)
      - The Construction Site (Box 38)
      - The Day After Memorial Day (Box 38)
      - The dog that barked for 4 hours & the rooster that/ crowed for 2 [first lines] (Box 38)
      - The Don Season [also exists as earlier version "New Year Sing Air"?] (Box 38)
      - The Feel of Milk (Box 38)
      - The first of the undecoded messages was… [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - The Flying Diary (Box 38)
      - The Good Roof [Root?] Protection (Box 38)
      - The HYENA speaks of Rotten bananas near [fl?] (Box 38)
      - The Land (old ballad) (Box 38)
      - The light green sea with white foam [fl; looks like a collaboration, collaborator unknown] (Box 38)
      - The Little Girl Who Liked Ice (Box 38)
      - The Lover Without Ostensible Motive [p. 2 related?] (Box 38)
      - The Interior of Our Aircraft (to acquaint you with) (Box 38)
      - The Midway [also includes "Inside Dallas"] (Box 38)
      - The Network (Box 38)
      - The Nun Abutsu [from the Therigatha or the Theragatha ?] (Box 38)
      - The Official Version (Box 38)
      - The Other (Box 38)
      - The POEM of Dad's Birthday [by Anne Waldman and Ambrose Bye] (Box 38)
      - The Problem, after Laura (Riding) Jackson (Box 38)
      - The Romance Thing (Box 38)
      - The Sofa Is Black (Box 38)
      - The span of life in these hills [or "hells"?] is also/ exact… [first lines; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - The Tundra & the Waves (Box 38)
      - The Vast [plus "The Domain dispersal" and "Another Breton Field in Brittany"; by Anne Waldman?] (Box 38)
      - The Wonderful Shapes of Elizabeth Murray (Box 38)
      - THC News (Box 38)
      - There's a man down the hall who's much [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - Things to Do at Home (Woman) (Box 38)
      - Thinking About You (Box 38)
      - Thinking of Chloe (Box 38)
      - Thinking Right Inside the Thing (Box 38)
      - This dark day this day this poor sad human day [fl; might be called "Devil's Work: Plutonium"] (Box 38)
      - This November, for Ted (Box 38)
      - Though I have a dozen lovers [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - Thoughts of the Dolphin, for my son Ambrose & in support of the efforts of Greenpeace on behalf of the dolphins (Box 38)
      - 3 Epiphanies (Box 38)
      - 3 Padgetts (Box 38)
      - "Three Stars" [fl; part of larger piece?] (Box 38)
      - Tigress [or "Excavation"?] (Box 38)
      - To a Roofer (Box 38)
      - To a Young Poet (Box 38)
      - To Down a Phantom (Box 38)
      - To Each a Willed By (Box 38)
      - To Greet a Letter-Carrier [by Anne Waldman?] (Box 38)
      - to John (Box 38)
      - To My Former Husband (Box 38)
      - to place these waters down for you [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - To Steve Carey (Box 38)
      - To the Censorious Ones (Box 38)
      - To the Russian Poet [and other works, attached: "I Wept Unto a Car"; "Circles"; "Tan"; "Saint"; "Troit," for Ann and Ken [Mikolowski?]; "Battery"; "Let's Get This Show on the Road! or The Collective Amnesia," for Kenward Elmslie; "Light & Shadow"] (Box 38)
      - To the Seventies (Box 38)
      - Toast (Box 38)
      - Today I write in the context of 4 white walls [first sentence of prose piece; May exist elsewhere under another title] (Box 38)
      - Too Bad Trains [or "Obsolete"?] (Box 38)
      - Toronto Untitled (Box 38)
      - Tough Instinctive (Box 38)
      - Toupee (Box 38)
      - Tract (Box 38)
      - Trait [orig. title "Traits"] (Box 38)
      - Traveler ["Homage to Basho the Traveler"] (Box 38)
      - trim or no: frost [fl; by Anne Waldman?] (Box 38)
      - Triolet (Box 38)
      - True [plus "Shut Up"] (Box 38)
      - True Stories from the Orient Express [comprised of "Contraband" and "The Bulgarian Conductor"] (Box 38)
      - True Story of Being at the Pool (Box 38)
      - Turkish Truckstop (Box 38)
      - Turning Into, for Molly (Box 38)
      - TV Marnie [or simply, "Marnie"] (Box 38)
      - 12 Hours (Box 38)
      - Two Men (Box 38)
      - 2 Nozzle Relics (Box 38)
      - Ubi Sunt (Box 38)
      - "Uh-Oh Plutonium!" and other poems, in Spanish translation (Box 38)
      - Uncharacteristic (Box 38)
      - Up to the very top I'm all forever green [fl] (Box 38)
      - valentine (Box 38)
      - Valentine Sonnets for Reed Bye [attached note, "Valentine Sonnets by Anne," "1978 ?"] (Box 38)
      - Valentines (Box 38)
      - Van Gogh's Room [attached note, "Countries"] (Box 38)
      - Various River (Box 38)
      - Vermeer cut-up with Ambrose's help (Box 38)
      - Village Blues (Box 38)
      - Villanelle (Box 38)
      - Virgil Variations, for Edmund Joseph Berrigan (Box 38)
      - Vision [alternate title, "Vision (Dope) & The Blood Body"] (Box 38)
      - Volcano (Box 38)
      - Wait [or "Waiting"] (Box 38)
      - Wake Up Poem (Box 38)
      - Walk Around Time [and/or "Pump & Painting"] (Box 38)
      - Wall (Box 38)
      - War [or "In Ruins"] (Box 38)
      - Warrior (song to myself) (Box 38)
      - Watervliet (Box 38)
      - Weather (Box 38)
      - Well Gone Dry (Box 38)
      - West Point (Box 38)
      - What Happened to Kerouac [review of What Happened to Kerouac, by Reed Bye and Anne Waldman] (Box 38)
      - What the Rocks Say, after Desnos [attached note, " Journals and Dreams (some rejects)"] (Box 38)
      - What's Around (Box 38)
      - What's Really Mine (Box 38)
      - While You Were Out More Concerning Love ["Collaboration w/Rene Ricard & A.W."] (Box 38)
      - White Eyes (Box 38)
      - White Rice (Box 38)
      - Who I was & what I wanted & what I did & what happened [fl; has another title?] (Box 38)
      - Wide Awake Workshop/ Snapshot Poetics (Box 38)
      - Wide Receiver (Box 38)
      - Widowed (Box 38)
      - Winding (Box 38)
      - Window On The World, [attached note, "1978--Draft of B-Day poem for T. Berrigan"] (Box 38)
      - Winter River (Box 38)
      - Within A Budding (Box 38)
      - Within With Within (Box 38)
      - Woman Girl, Lover, Wind in Foothills A Poet [title?; last page related?] (Box 38)
      - Wonder (Box 38)
      - Writing Writing Writing Writing Research Dreaming Walking [for a Naropa course?] (Box 38)
      - Yard Heap Chant ["written for Earth Day 1997"] (Box 38)
      - Yes & No (Box 38)
      - you mean nothing to me but noise [fl; fragment?] (Box 38)
      - You Reduce Me To An Object Of Desire (Box 38)
      - You, Robert Lowell, for Robert Creeley (Box 38)
      - You See All This Freedom??????????? (Box 38)
      - Young Love (Box 38)
      - you're like ice (Box 38)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 38)
      - Fragments
        (May include some whole, untitled works)
        - Partial proofs of an unidentified work, sent from Phillip Gallo at Hermetic Press, 1996-1997 (Box 38)
        - General (Box 38)
      - Miscellaneous photocopies of published poetry (Box 38)
      - Unidentified: title and sometimes author unknown (4 folders) (Box 38)
  - Contributions to Other Works
    - Best Minds: A Tribute to Allen Ginsberg, plus correspondence, 1984 (Box 38)
    - Going on Our Nerve, 2002 (Box 38)
    - The Pleasures of the Flesh: Poems, selected by Barbara and Sam Abrams, undated (Box 38)
    - Poems for the Millennium: the University of California Book of Modern & Postmodern Poetry, Jerome Rothenberg and Pierre Joris, eds. (Box 38)
    - The New Amazing Grace, Ed Sanders, ed., ? ca. 1994 (Box 38)
    - Belladonna *26 [Things] Seen/Unseen. Published for reading at Bluestockings Women's Bookstore, Spring 2002 (Box 38)
    - Thuggery and Grace, co-edited with Erik Anderson.Issue #4 draft. November 2008 (Box 38)
    - Magazine submissions, 1995-2003 (Box 38)
    - Calendar poems by Anne Waldman and illustrations by Rikki Ducornet, drafts included, undated (Box 38)
      Signed copy out of 201 copies 26 signed by author and artist,
    - Rules of the House by Tsering Wangmo Dhompa, 2002 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 38)
- Journals and Notebooks
  The Journals and Notebooks series (5 linear feet) consists of more than 110 journals, notebooks, appointment books, and address books kept by Anne Waldman. A small number of journals kept by others is also represented. The journals offer a diverse array of content, from random jottings and to-do lists, to literary notes and drafts, to intensely personal diaries.
  - Anne Waldman (journals, notebooks, appointment books)
    - 1960s, 17 volumes and 1 envelope) (Box 39)
      (includes some pages of Frances Waldman's address book?)
    - 1970s, 38.0 volumes (Box 40)
      (includes a journal, ca. 1974-1977 with a portrait of Anne by Bob Dylan)
    - 1980s, 17.0 volumes (Box 41)
    - 1990s, 2.0 volumes (Box 41)
      (includes one oversize calendar from 1990 stored in box 31)
    - 1990s and undated, 32.0 volumes (Box 42)
  - Others
    - [Bye, Reed]
      - Loose pages, 1977 (Box 43)
      - 1979 (Box 43)
    - Warsh, Lewis
      - 1960-1961 (Box 43)
      - Journal written with Anne Waldman, undated (Box 43)
- Editing and Publishing
  The Editing and Publishing series (approximately 12.5 linear feet) is comprised of Anne Waldman's work in editing and publishing, often as a joint venture with those in her circle. The Small Press and Little Magazine subseries, represents her work with The Poetry Project at St. Mark's Church-in-the-Bowery, Angel Hair, Full Court Press, Rocky Ledge, and Cherry Valeey.
  The remainer of the series is arranged by individual book titles, and miscellaneous contracts, proposals, copyright application material, and financial material. Unpublished materials includes miscellaneous pieces of writing that could be part of books that are published or unpublished or drafts of works with an unknown title.
  - Small Press and Little Magazine
    - The Poetry Project at St. Mark's Church-in-the-Bowery
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - Daniel Kane to Anne Waldman re dissertation on the Poetry Project, November 1997 (Box 44)
          - Frances LeFevre: incoming
            - Newsletter requests, notes, and ephemera, 1977-1978 (Box 44)
            - Newsletter submissions with cover letters, 1971-1980, undated (Box 44)
            - Newsletter submission and church-related material, 1974-1979, undated (Box 44)
            - Assorted, 1971-1974 (Box 44)
        - Loose Poems: distributed singly, undated (Box 44)
        - Administrative Material: schedules, reports, notes, minutes, budgets, 1974-1981, undated (Box 44)
        - Study Abroad on the Bowery Program (2 folders), 2005-2006 (Box 44)
        - Bowery Arts & Science, LTD. 2007, 2009 (Box 44)
        - Performances
          - Programs and Flyers, 1970-1997, undated (Box 44)
          - Catalogue of Audio (and Video) Tapes: Readings, Performances, Workshops and Lectures at the St. Mark's Poetry Project, 1970-1979, compiled by Harvey Lillywhite (Box 44)
          - Readings & Events at the St. Mark's Poetry Project, 1966-2004, undated (Box 44)
          - Speeches and Introductions, 1975-1984, undated (Box 44)
        - The Poetry Project Newsletter
          - Manuscript submissions and letters, 1977-1978 (Box 44)
          - Newsletter issues
            - #1-28, 1973-1975 (Box 44)
            - #31-42, January 1976-February 1977 (Box 44)
            - #44-50, April 1977-December 1977 (Box 44)
            - #51-60, January 1978-December 1978 (Box 44)
            - #61-79, January 1979-January 1981 (Box 44)
            - #80-109, February 1981-November 1984 (Box 44)
            - #111-120, January 1985-March 1986 (Box 44)
            - #127-135, April 1988-January 1990 (Box 44)
            - #136-147, #149, February 1990-May 1993 (Box 44)
            - #154-219, November 1994-June 2009 (Box 44)
      - Adventures in Poetry: edited and published at St. Mark's Church by Larry Fagin
        - Manuscript fragments: Belgrade, November 19, 1963, Frank O'Hara (Box 44)
        - Publications, 1972-1973,1975 (Box 44)
      - The World
        - Administrative Material
          - Author-title Index, 1979 (Box 45)
          - Material re Dreams by Peter Schjeldahl, 1973, undated (Box 45)
          - Other: minutes, mailing lists, etc., 1972, undated (Box 45)
        - Submissions: manuscripts and related correspondence, alphabetical by author, plus additional folders
          - A-B (Box 45)
          - C (Box 45)